I think going into it, I think we have
to assume macro headwinds going into
early 2026. Do you think we're in a bare
market? But I could see it potentially
being over as early as May.
>> What is the reasoning?
>> You can never convince people to get in
when they should because like it's not
cool to buy crypto when when the prices
are low and so they'll ignore you and
then eventually they listen to [music]
you. They'll listen to you at a peak and
then they'll blame you after that.
Markets humble everyone. The worst thing
is [music] if you're wrong doubling down
when you are wrong. That's the worst
thing.
Our favorite Ben Cohen is here with me
at Binance Blockchain Week. He is the
founder of Into the Cryptoverse and
one of the smartest people I know.
>> I appreciate that, but I'm [laughter]
not.
>> People call you the fortune teller
because a lot of times you come to our
show and you say, "Hey, this is going to
happen." Last time you said it was
November 14th, something around that.
And then whatever you predicted actually
happened.
>> Okay. I don't remember what it was, but
[laughter]
yeah. Yeah, I mean I think I've been on
your channel cross
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I think uh I think a lot
of times I've been on your I think I was
on your channel maybe in early 2025 as
well cuz we talked a little bit about
like Salana Bitcoin and I was talking
about how it was going to go down like
Salana's Bitcoin valuation is going to
go down. It's kind of like following
Ethereum's Bitcoin valuation.
>> Um but yeah, I mean like it's it's
really interesting time in the market
because people are like is it a bull
market? Is it a bare market?
>> It's a fair market.
>> Yeah, I mean I I think so. I but I think
it's it's it's very similar to prior
bare markets in the sense that it's like
we're topping in Q4 of the posttop year
like we always do. Q4, 2013, 2017, 2021
were all the peaks and then we had bare
markets. But what's different is that we
topped on apathy rather than euphoria.
And that's more similar to 2019. Um and
what's also similar to 2019 is social
interest was really really low. It was
when quantitative tightening came to an
end in 2019. Bitcoin topped out a couple
of months before QT ended. And now it
looks like it's doing the same thing. It
topped in October. QT ends in December.
Um it it's really reminiscent of those
market conditions. And so when you have
a nonuporic top, what it means is that
you don't have So from euphoric tops,
you have all the retail that comes in
and buys the top and then they usually
lead to these like brutal bare markets,
right? Because they're they're selling.
>> Yeah. When you have a non- euphoric top
like 2019, you still have a bare market,
but it's more of like a slower
progression of people just kind of like
slowly giving up is what it was back
then. And what happened was, and what's
really interesting is that like some
people out there, we just did a talk
about, you're talking about content
creation, and someone was talking about
to me, they're like, you know, should I
is now a good time to start a YouTube
channel? And I'm like, well, you know,
in 2019 when I started my YouTube
channel, these were basically these same
market conditions.
>> QT was about to end. No, Bitcoin had
just topped out. No one cared about
crypto. Retail was not here. No one
cared. And I started my channel and no
one cared for a while and then monetary
policy changed and then everything
changed. I mean, I do think we're in a
bare market. Um, but I could see it, you
know, potentially being over as early as
May. Um, realistically, I think you have
to go into it assuming it it very well
easily could take until next October as
well, cuz all primary markets have been
one year. um with the exception of sort
of that intermediate bare market we had
in 2019. So I think going into it I
think we have to assume macro headwinds
going into early 2026 though I do think
there will be a a bare market rally in
early 2026.
>> What is the reasoning?
>> So normally because think about it like
this most people went into Q4 assuming
we would have this like massive blowoff
top with an all season. Yeah. And so
that didn't happen right? We had a high.
We had a new all-time high, but it was
not really a massive blowoff top. And I
think from there, people gave up, right?
People have been selling. They're like,
"All right, cycle's over." After you
have about three months of selling in a
bare market, usually you have a counter
trend rally. So, if you look at 2021, we
had um November, December, and January
were all red months. And then in
February and March, we had a bare market
rally back up to the 200 day moving
average and or the 50we moving average.
So, I think right now you're you're
seeing kind of a lot of selling based on
people just being like, "All right,
cycle's over." You know, and then I
think in early 2026,
you're going to have all those people
that are going to sell. They're going to
be gone in the short term. You're going
to be left with the people that are are
holding on. And I think it will lead to
uh a bare market rally in early 2026.
But my guess is it's going to be a lower
high by Bitcoin. You could have some
divergent higher highs on some alts,
though. Like it's possible there there
are scenarios where certain
cryptocurrencies could go to new
all-time highs even though Bitcoin might
put in a lower high. Um but we're not at
that point yet. Like I don't think we're
in that rally just yet. But we're in a
rally right now as I speak to you
because we're back at 93K. But I don't
think this is the you know I'm not
really convinced that this yet is the
the big rally to take us back up above,
you know, what people think is possible.
I think in the short term people have
really given up. I think you're going to
see some short-term um you know
short-term moves back to the downside.
But I do think you'll have that that you
don't really have you ask me like why,
right? But I mean you don't always have
to have a reason. Sometimes if everyone
starts betting on the downside, then
usually there's just a squeeze back up
to the upside, you know, and that also
happened in 2019 as well. Um so I I
think I think that's what's going to
happen. I think you you have downside,
you have a counter trend rally into
early 2026. It's going to make people
think that the cycle's not over and then
we're going to have another drop kind of
going into into the summer and then that
could be the low. Like I'm open-minded
to that being the low, but we'll have to
see what's going on at the time and and
see how far down Bitcoin even is by that
point. So,
>> I find it very interesting that you look
at numbers all day, but then you're
like, "Okay, I want to guess what people
would think when they see the numbers
and I want to create a strategy around
that." But how do you know if your guess
is correct?
>> I don't I mean like I I'm telling people
what I think's going to happen. I always
hedge. I mean like even though I think
we're in a bare market, I still do own
like both Bitcoin and Ethereum. Um and
like there does exist scenario where
Ethereum goes to another all-time high.
Like it's possible for that to happen.
Um but like I think it's important to
have a plan. like you know you you like
I think what I think and I will base a
lot of my strategy around that but I
always hedge in case I'm wrong because
sometimes I do get things wrong and like
when I get it wrong I I don't want to be
completely on the wrong side of the
market right like having some Bitcoin if
we're in a bare market um protects me
from potentially falling into the trap
of buying into a bare market rally right
like if we have a bare market rally in
early 2026 and I don't own any Bitcoin
it would be easy to then want to FOMO
back in at at the next lower high. But
if I have some, then I don't really feel
like I'm missing out on anything. Like,
all right, well, I have some. I'm, you
know, I can I can enjoy the ride.
>> Do you ever look at the news?
>> Sometimes, but I don't really base my
decisions on the news. Like, I think
like it's interesting to know what's
happening, but I don't really think the
markets are often moving in a in a um in
an ongoing way based on the news. I
mean, obviously if Trump comes out and
tweets something about the crypto
markets, like it can have a short-term
effect like on that minute candle,
>> but you don't care about that.
>> I don't care about that because I don't
a lot of that stuff is just fleeting.
Like no one even cares a few month a few
days later like people forget and they
move on. I don't really think that stuff
matters as much.
>> What about all the DAT companies? People
are spreading FUD on all the Bitcoin
treasury companies. Does that even
matter? I mean, I think it's it's nice
narratives um to sort of justify like
why, you know, why we could have a bare
market, right? Um but the reality is we
always have bare markets every four
years, you know, like it's just like,
yeah, we have bare markets every four
years because people get greedy. Some of
the treasury companies get greedy. They
they end up buying the top. Um and their
cost basis might be over 100k, you know,
who knows? Um and and the way the market
punishes them is by going down and and
punishing them for being so late. And
the people that weren't late can stomach
the draw downs. The people that came in
this late are going to be punished and
they're Yeah. Like not all of them are
going to survive. Some of them will go
down and and that will be part of the
reason for why people say the bare
market's happening. But there's always a
reason. Um and you know the winds just
change. Like the music doesn't go on
forever. The music turns off sometimes
and when it turns off the uh the zombie
companies go to zero. And and it's a
good thing because then it it helps
those people that work for those
companies to to then go work for other
companies that are more beneficial to
society, you know. So I mean when the
markets go down, um it just allows the
companies that are doing well to to
survive and thrive long term and it and
it gets rid of all the other froth.
>> We were talking earlier on stage about
your content creation journey and I find
it really really interesting. You said
you were intentionally
making boring thumbnails when you first
started. What does that even mean? Yeah,
I mean I I didn't want to do the
clickbait stuff essentially is I also
wanted to attract people that weren't
attracted to really clickbaity stuff
because I know that clickbait stuff is
fleeting and that people want to um feel
like they're not being sold something
constantly and I just wanted to provide
like a boring opinion, you know, and I
was like, "All right, I'll match my
opinion my boring videos with boring
thumbnails." I also just was too lazy to
go and find someone to make thumbnails
for me. Um, and so the easiest thing to
do was just to make the thumbnail be
either just a picture of the chart I was
going to be talking about or yeah, maybe
just putting the title on there in bold
yellow letters and just moving on
because ultimately what I felt back then
was that people valued like what I had
to say about certain charts. They valued
what I had to say a lot more than just
like the thumbnail that got them there
in the first place. So in the short term
it's hard harder to grow because you're
not getting the clickbait people. But in
the long term, it's better because you
attract the people that are more serious
and they're the you attract the people
that aren't going to leave when things
go south, you know? Yeah.
>> So, clickbait attracts people that will
immediately leave. And that's why you
have certain channels that have a lot of
followers, but when you look at their
views,
>> they're not really getting a whole lot
of views because most of their followers
were achie Yeah. They were bought or
achieved through very clickbaity things
and um they're gone. So,
>> but I use this analogy. So, thumbnails
and your branding is more like the
storefront and how do you get people to
come in first and then to see that my
stuff is good. But yeah, like you said,
there's a balance and it's very hard for
most people to find that balance.
>> Well, and now I have AI thumbnails,
right? So, had I had those a had I had
AI back then, I probably would have been
using it. A lot of it was just me being
lazy and and not wanting to to to spend
the time to to create the thumbnail. Um,
but also like when I was doing it back
in 2019 and 2020, I like I was working
as a posttock in, you know, at a
national lab. Like I like I wasn't doing
YouTube to grow a large audience. I was
doing YouTube to just like express some
ideas and that was about it. Like I
didn't think I would ever have, you
know, nearly a million subscribers. I
never thought I'd have 10,000
subscribers, you know, like I didn't
think people would find it interesting.
Um and then I and then that started to
happen and then AI was, you know, AI
kind of um hit in what, like 2022 and
Chat GPT and and then I started doing
the AI thumbnail. So, it's a good mix.
Um but yeah, that's how that's how I got
started. Very slow growth at first, but
then I think people valued the content.
>> Was it a very wellthoughtout plan?
you're like, I want to be boring and
this is how I attract these group of
people and then
>> this is
>> I don't know. I mean, like I I think I
was maybe more like playing checkers
rather than chess about it back then. I
It was It was like all right, I'm just
I'm not going to to do the clickbait
style because that's what everyone else
is doing. I just want to be different
and this is one way that I can
distinguish myself and
>> maybe it works, maybe it doesn't.
>> That was when 20
>> 2019 20 2019
>> 2019. Yeah.
>> And a lot of other channels
>> were dead.
>> Yeah. And then also like I saw a lot of
people kind of complaining about all the
clickbait and stuff and I was like, "All
right, well, I'll try to be different
and see how it goes." Yeah. And for a
long time it didn't go well because no
one could find my channel because I
wasn't using clickbait stuff, you know.
Um, again, it took me six months to go
from like zero subscribers to 500 and I
was posting, you know, a video or two a
week and there was like no growth and
then at some point everything changed.
Like the algorithms picked me up.
>> Was it like depressing at first? because
I have friends that start new channels
and they would think it's embarrassing
to tell people that, you know, I'm
starting to make content now with, let's
say, a hundred followers. They don't
want to tell people they're doing this.
>> I still don't tell people.
>> But people know people know you.
>> Well, people at conferences know me, but
like when I go home
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah.
>> people don't know me. I don't really get
recognized hardly ever. Actually, the
places I get recognized the most are
like children's museums because I take
my kids there and then like their dads
will often recognize me. Like other kids
dads will recognize me or if I go on
vacation, I'll get recognized, but
that's about it. I don't really get
recognized a whole lot.
>> Well, isn't it fun to share with people
what you do though?
>> I don't usually tell people
>> at all.
>> No.
>> In real life,
>> I I just say like I have my own company.
Um, and it's based around like
quantitative finance
>> and and then people stop asking, right?
Cuz it's too difficult.
>> Yeah. It's like saying it's like saying
like I'm an accountant. Like no one
really is like all right whatever you do
that. Um but then every once in a while
like I'll be with some friends and then
like someone will recognize me in public
and they're like what what's going on?
Like they have no idea like and then
>> or like I'll be on a channel and someone
will recognize me and they're like wait
like you have like I saw you on this
channel like you know.
>> Um so that happens. I don't really go
into public and try to convince people
because what what happens is like you
can never convince people to to get in
when they should because like it's not
cool to buy crypto when when the prices
are low. Um and so they'll ignore you
and and then eventually they listen to
you but they listen to you they'll be
like oh they'll they'll they'll listen
to you at a peak. So like they'll ignore
you when they should have gotten in,
they'll buy at a peak and then they'll
blame you after that for the next year.
So there's really not like a it's really
not a great it's like almost like a
lose-lose scenario. So it's like people
have to come up people have to figure
out for themselves this is what they
want to do and and then take on the
responsibility. I don't want to be the
person out there trying to convince
people and then they buy the top and
they blame me. Um so I think that's one
of the reasons why I kind of just shy
away from it because I used to try to
convince people. Yeah.
>> You know and
>> people love you for a very short period
of time and they hate you for the bare
market year and then they sell and then
they wish they hadn't and yeah it's just
a brutal cycle. So, what do you say to
people when they ask you? If they know
what you do, they will ask you.
>> Yeah, I mean, I'll tell them my honest
opinion. Like, so if people ask me like
now like what they should do, I'm I
would say generally we're in a bare
market. So, like kind of just expect
that for for a little while and um like
the winds will probably shift sometime
next year, but we're not we're not at
that point yet. And and also for the
long term, like focus mostly on Bitcoin.
look at the valuation of altcoins
against Bitcoin, not against the US
dollar because if you look at it against
Bitcoin, you'll start to understand like
why Bitcoin dominance matters and that
kind of stuff. Um, so that's what I
generally tell people.
>> How do you motivate yourself to post
every single day?
>> Yeah, I mean I I mean the markets are
always changing like some some things
going on in the market, right? Even
though there's a bare market, there's
always a bull market somewhere. So like
even yesterday I posted a video about
silver, you know. Um because I I've been
very bullish on commodities for a while
like gold, silver, platium, uranium. Um
I also like think that if I stop posting
then people
are going to go somewhere else, you
know? So like I want to post because I
know there's a lot of people that want
to listen to what I have to say or just
be updated about the markets in general.
And and it's easy to do. Like it doesn't
take me a ton of time. Like I don't plan
my videos. Like I just I'll be playing
chess on my computer and I'll be like,
"All right, I guess I'll go make a
video."
>> You're joking.
>> Yeah.
>> What?
>> No. Yeah. I don't plan them at all. Like
I just I get up, I go to my computer,
and I'm like, "All right, what am I
going to talk about?" And then I look at
the charts. I'm like, "I'll talk about
this." And I record it and then I post
it all within about 20 minutes or so. Um
because I don't edit them at all.
>> I know.
>> Yeah. Um so I just do that. It doesn't
take a lot of time. Um
>> it's mostly just about, you know,
thinking about where the markets are
going and trying to provide an opinion
on it.
um when I get things wrong trying to be
as early as I can be about saying when
I'm wrong because the worst thing is if
you're wrong doubling down when you are
wrong that's the worst thing you know so
you have to be you have to be really
willing to pivot when you are wrong and
I think that actually can distinguish a
lot of people like you know certain
creators from other creators is like
especially if you're making predictions
about financial markets which the
markets humble everyone the the people
that I really respect the most that make
predictions are the ones that will admit
they're they're wrong about certain
things. Um because they're not trying to
like pretend there's something they're
not, you know, like I mean a lot of
people say I've get a lot of things
right and I mean I think I've gone on a
kind of like a I got a lucky streak for
for the last couple years or so, but the
reality is like I do get things wrong
and I'll be wrong in the future. And um
you know, we have to remind ourselves
that like no one actually knows what's
happening. You know, like I think we're
in a bare market. Maybe I'm wrong. maybe
Bitcoin goes to new high and and if it
does like I'll be happy actually, you
know, because at least I held on to some
of it, you know. Um yeah, I mean I think
I think the motivation to keep posting
is is to just be like, you know what,
there's still people that are interested
in what I have to say, so this is my
job.
>> I heard somebody said the best way to
build like a cult following is to stick
to what you've said. Never admit you're
wrong.
I disagree with that wholeheartedly and
I know a lot of people that do that and
honestly like I know some people that do
it that have been really successful even
politicians that that never admit when
they're wrong and I don't know like I
don't agree with it. I think integrity
is a big thing and I think people
respect when you are willing to admit
you're wrong because it kind of reminds
you that hey like you're human you know
you're not perfect. They shouldn't think
that you're perfect. They really
shouldn't put you up on a pedestal. Um,
and I I think like I think if you never
admit you're wrong, people the people
that follow you over a long enough
period of time, like they'll realize
what you're doing and that will detract
from your brand. Um, so it's better to
just admit you're wrong and take
ownership of it.
>> Have you ever said something online that
you know you later realize it's wrong
and then you apologize?
>> With financial markets, the first thing
is no one knows what's going to happen,
right? So, like we're all going to get
things wrong. I don't know if you have
to like I don't know if I have to
apologize if I get things wrong because
like I'm already kind of saying upront,
hey, like I could be wrong about this.
>> Um but I think you have to admit that
you're wrong. Like if you say something
>> and it doesn't happen, you have to come
out and be like, all right, I was wrong
about that. Rather than pretending like
it doesn't happen.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so and and the the the if I ever make
shorter term predictions, those are more
likely to be wrong than longer term
predictions. Um, so and that happens
more frequently. Like sometimes I'll
branch out and be like, "All right, this
is what I think is going to happen in
the short term and those are more likely
to be wrong because in the short term
you could argue that markets follow
geometric brownie in motion, like a
random walk, which is completely
unpredictable." Um, so I don't really
think you need to apologize for being
wrong, but I think you need to admit
when you are because, you know, there's
people that really showed Luna a lot
last cycle and US and and talking about
that kind of stuff or Celsius or Voyager
or FTX, like all these different
platforms. And I think if you know, I
think that's a good reason to sort of
say, "Hey, I'm sorry. I was wrong." And
then you move on. like it doesn't mean
you can't recover from it, but if you
don't ever admit you're wrong um or
apologize, I think you you will lose
like the trust of a lot of people. And
it's it's so hard. Like it can be really
hard to to apologize. Um but I do think
it's important and kind of like
repairing relationships with the people
that watch you.
>> You have to really use or really believe
in what you use or promote,
>> right? You have to do your due
diligence. You have to believe in it.
You can't just because it's easy to take
money if you were financially
incentivized to do that. If you were
paid to do it, um you are kind of taking
on responsibility, right? You I feel
like it's hard to just be like, "Oh, no,
I don't have any responsibility." Um
that's why I think it's more like more
okay to that's why it's more justified
to apologize for those things. But if
you're just providing an opinion that's
not paid for, you know, you're allowed
to have an opinion. You're allowed to be
wrong about things. You know, we all be
wrong.
>> You also talk about silver and um metals
and stuff. H how how does that relate to
crypto?
>> Well, I mean there's just always a bull
market somewhere and I think like as
content creators like the the one thing
that will never go away is people that
want to invest to make money. Yeah.
>> Right. Whether it's crypto, commodities,
stocks, bonds, whatever money market
account, T bills, right? People always
want to make money. Um and there's
always a bull market somewhere. So, when
you're in a period like we're we are
we've been in for the last year or so
where the crypto markets aren't really
moving, there's only so many times I can
say the same thing, you know, or I'm
like, "All right, there's people get
that Bitcoin has been at 100K for the
last year." And they get that, yeah,
maybe we're in a bare market, but like
maybe they still have money they want to
put somewhere. They maybe they don't
want to put it in Bitcoin right now
because they also believe it's a bare
market. They want to put it somewhere
else. So then that's why I talk about
other things like there's there's a bull
market somewhere at all times and it's
just figuring out where those bull
markets are. To me it doesn't matter if
it's ticker ABC or DEF like it doesn't
matter. It's you know why does it matter
if you make 20% on on Bitcoin versus
silver or gold or uranium or Ethereum it
doesn't matter at the end of the day.
It's just you're making money. That's
why like people will say like with the
whole Bitcoin dominance like you're a
toxic Bitcoin maxi you know is what I
heard. I was like, I don't like I'm just
trying to preserve my wealth, right? And
like I'd rather hold Bitcoin than than
it's like a micro cap altcoin for the
next four years. Yeah. You know, so it's
not about being a maxi. It's just about
preserving wealth over the long haul.
>> So from what you're saying, it is a bull
market in silver.
>> Yeah, it's been a bull market in metals
for a while. But I do think my general
thought process is that is that metals
will probably cool off a little bit in
2026. Um, but I do think they'll
continue to do well for the rest of the
decade is my guess. A lot of times
metals are in like decade long bull
markets. Um, silver just broke through
its prior all-time highs from like 2011.
Um, I could see it getting a pullback
below those, you know, back down in uh,
2026, but ultimately I think they will
go higher um, as we go as we go further
on. gold gold normally does well during
exact market conditions like this when
you know especially prefed printing you
know like with inflation and and all
that stuff people flock to hard assets
and you know commodities are are
something that you can't just print you
know you can't just go print gold um you
can mine more of it right you can you
can do that but you can't just go print
it and so that's one of the reasons why
>> metals do well during times like this
and especially during times of
uncertainty because risk assets really
hate uncertainty and there's been a lot
of uncertainty um in the last year.
>> I find it very interesting that people
have been talking about uh gold and
metal because to the younger generation
those are like the boring stuff, the old
people's stuff. But it's uh trendy
again.
>> That's because prices are going up.
>> Exactly. And if
>> while gold has these characteristics of
being scarce and all that, it's been
like that forever. Why is it only
happening now? because gold went through
a massive bull market in the 2000s like
and so like I was born in 1990 and so
during the last major gold bull market
like I was a kid you know I was 10 years
old when it started and by the time it
was over in 2011 I was 21 like I wasn't
really an investor and so I think a lot
of us are products of our experience and
so I graduated like I mean I I graduated
undergrad in 2012 And so, ever since
I've really been investing, all we've
ever known is that risk assets
outperform commodities. You know, like
we've seen Bitcoin outperform gold for
forever basically. Um, and then you have
people like Peter Schiff who are
speaking, you know, here at the
conference who, you know, you you have
to think like why do they have these
opinions? Like why do they think that
like commodities are are where to be and
they can be wrong. I mean, you know,
they can be wrong for years and years
and years. It doesn't mean they're
always going to be wrong. And the reason
they're so opinionated is the same
reason that we are so opinionated about
Bitcoin is because we we saw it go up
for a decade, more than a decade. He's
seen gold go up in the 2000s. He
probably also saw it go up in the 70s
and the 80s when we had inflationary,
you know, issues. So he knows that it's
only a matter of time before gold, you
know, outperforms risk assets. like he
knows it's only a matter of time and
that's why you can he can sit up there
and and say very confidently it's going
to happen and as long as he has at least
a 10-year time horizon like he's going
to eventually be right.
>> Um so I think that's one of the reasons
I think a lot of people have a hard time
especially my age kind of like accepting
that commodities are are in the bull
market and cryptos in a bear is because
like they've never really seen that
environment but it doesn't mean those
environments never exist. they do exist
and it's exactly that type of
environment that will then make those
people probably a little bit more
diversified in the future and then
they'll be like the old people they're
like oh why do you have to have gold in
the per you know trying to convince the
younger generation of like you know
diversifying somewhat um so I I'm trying
like it's I can look at a chart and look
at Bitcoin be like all right it
generally goes up and to the right but I
can also look at gold and see that every
20 30 years it has a massive bull market
And I don't want to just sit here and
and ignore it just because it's like,
you know, something that only old people
own. I'd rather kind of like respect
what the what the data says. And if I
think gold's going to go up, then I want
it in my portfolio.
>> People can argue that we have a new form
of gold. So the history is not going to
repeat itself.
>> You talking about Bitcoin? Yes. Yeah. I
I don't see I disagree with that. Like I
Bitcoin trades like a risk asset. It
does not trade like a riskoff asset. It
never has. Maybe it will at some point,
but it's never traded as a riskoff
asset. It's traded like a levered
version of the NASDAQ. The NASDAQ's up
over 100%. Bitcoin went up like 700%
since 2022. That's why Bitcoin drops a
lot more in bare markets because it goes
up a lot more in bull markets. Um, it's
not a bad thing that Bitcoin is a
risk-on asset because over the long
haul, risk assets tend to do better.
There there's more times of risk-on
environments than riskoff environments,
right? You'll have periods where gold
outperforms, but there's longer periods
where stocks outperform and risk assets
outperform. So, it's not a bad thing
that Bitcoin is a is a risk on asset. It
it does not trade like gold at all. And
um and I mean, you look at the last
year, like I mean, if Bitcoin traded
like gold, it would be up a lot more
>> because gold's up a lot. Bitcoin's down.
So, I mean, that's kind of clear
evidence that they they they're not
really correlated and they're inversely
correlated over, you know, probably
longer periods of time. I It depends on
it depends on what you're looking at. I
mean, if you look at it from, you know,
from when Bitcoin started to now, like
they've both gone up. So, in a sense
that you could say they're positively
correlated, but over certain time
frames, like risk off versus risk on,
like there's times where they're
completely inversely, they're negatively
correlated, where one goes up, the other
goes down.
>> I think you're right about us never
seeing
gold outperform these stocks and like
Bitcoin and stuff. So it is very hard
for us to understand which leads to
people saying that during very scary
moments in the world like in the history
something bad really bad has to happen
for these you know gold silver to go up
>> and people are expecting something
really bad is going to happen soon la is
your view
>> I think there's still some runway for
the AI um stuff I mean like I don't know
exactly when the music's going to stop.
I mean, it probably will stop at some
point. I mean, it's a natural
progression of the business cycle. Um,
there there's a I could see a scenario
where PAL is replaced as chair. They put
someone in, they lower rates, they
reignite the animal spirits. Like,
that's possible. Um, that could even
lead to attention back on crypto maybe
in 2027, 2028 time frame. But eventually
I think they will have to face the music
of like you can't just lower rates and
print money to solve our problems
forever because if you do the the the
bond vigilantes are going to come back
there like rates are going to go up. You
know longend rates are going to go up. I
think at some point over the next like
two to three years the music will stop
um and there will be a big crash. But I
also think it's like a complete fool's
errand to try to time that. Like you
can't time it. There's not it's not
worth trying to time. Most people just
make fools of themselves trying to time
it. Um, so I think for now, for me, for
for crypto in general, like I'm just
going to stick to this to this cycle
behavior and eventually it'll break. Um,
and when it breaks, I'll admit I'm
wrong. But until that time, just if it's
not broke, don't fix it. It's like the
uh the four-year cycle is not even
unique to Bitcoin. Um, if you look at
the stock market in the ' 60s, '7s, and
early 80s, it was a four-year cycle.
there were major lows in the stock
market in 1966, 1970, 74,78 and 82.
Every four years there was a major low
and then you would have gone into ' 86
thinking, all right, we're going to have
a major low in ' 86 and then we didn't.
It we ended up having it in ' 87
instead. Um so you could argue the
four-year cycle has existed before
Bitcoin.
>> Why it could be based on presidential
cycles, right? um if Bitcoin's havingss
had been put in midterm years instead of
instead of election years like you know
we probably would have seen completely
different moves like Bitcoin maybe would
have bottomed around the having and then
we would have said oh it bottoms always
at the having instead of being halfway
through a bull market in the having so I
think that's the reason um but I do
think the four-year cycle will break
eventually um I'm just not going to be
the person calling for it to you know
like when it breaks it breaks and then
we we kind of adjust our views but until
that time I think if it's not broke
don't fix it and you're going to be
right more often than you're going to be
wrong.
>> Ben, thank you so much for being on the
show. By the way, you you look amazing
today. [laughter]
>> This is the first
>> I don't dress up very frequently.
>> Who made you do this?
>> I I I did it myself, believe it or not.
>> I love it. I love it. It matches your
eye color and everything. Thank you.
>> Thank you so much for being on on the
show.
>> Yeah. Thanks for having me. Pleasure to
be here his eyes.